Hardik Kamothi

Principal Engineer

B/103, Silver Harmony Near ICB Flora, Gota, Ahmedabad. 382481 (+91) 9737208790 hardikkamothi@gmail..com

7+ years of experience in design & development in mobile technologies with various tools & frameworks. Work on Custom Android Ported devices, Android Framework development, Android Application development & IoT Products.

- Work on Android framework & native applications.
- Strong experience in developing IoT based projects.
- Experience in streaming based applications.
- Experience in Multimedia domain.
- Experience in integrating AWS, Ayla & Evrythng IoT Cloud frameworks.
- Experience in working with remote data via Web Services, Socket Communications.
- Experience in Android UL Design and understanding of full mobile development life cycle.
- Good knowledge on Web Applications.
- Experience in cloud based and chatting based applications.
- Experience in BLE & MQTT protocols for communications.
- Experience of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) & Agile methodology.

Be a part of completed successfully 25+ projects having multiple-domains include Medical , IOT Products, E-Commerce, Live Streaming , Manufacturing and Utility Products.

I am also a core team member to mentor trainees and intermediate engineer by sharing my professional experience and knowledge with team for various technical aspects and clients requirements.

SKILLS		
Languages/Script		
	ì	Java
	ì	Android
	ì	Android NDK
	ì	PHP
	ì	JS
	ì	Jquery
Database		
	1	, .
	ì	•
	Ì	Big Query
Tools		
	ì	Android Studio
	ì	Eclipse
	ì	ADB
	ì	POSTMAN
Application Servers		
	ì	AWS
Version/Source Control		
	ì	Git
	ì	GitHub
	ì	BitBucket
	ì	JIRA
	ì	Confluence
	ì	Trello
Operating System		
	ì	Linux
	ì	Mac

■ Windows

EXPERIENCE

Volansys — Principal Engineer

JUNE 2015 - PRESENT

- Architect Mobility & Embedded Products
- CI/CD Process
- Manage JIRA, GIT
- Gained customer confidence by delivering consistent quality software projects.
- Played a key role on the design, development and implementation of POS system.
- Requirement gathering, Business process mapping and GAP Analysis for implementation of POS system. Involved in several internal projects like Streaming Projects, Embedded communication through mobile platform.
- Managed internal team along with customer's team and led them successfully to deliver enterprise projects. Established effective client communication and achieved sign offs and timely delivery of project.
- Define and coordinate the technical tasks for the development of the software and/or interfaces

ZealousWeb — SR Software Engineer

JUNE 2013 - APRIL 2015

- Lead the initiative to develop and implement Android coding flow architecture for projects.
- Gathered client requirements, analyzed, mapped and documented the business process requirements and offered suitable solutions.
- Designed, developed, documented and delivered product enhancements for customer.
- Performed system design enhancements to meet gaps identified between requirement and product functionality.
- Played key role in the design, development and implementation of POS system integration with Server and implement the flow of web services.
- Managed and motivated team members to deliver in more aggressive and challenging environments.

AWARDS

First Rank in All Semesters

Honoured to receive a trophies by Trustee HGCE

Innovation Idea

Honoured to receive a trophy by Vice Chancellor of GTU.

Uninor Social Challenge World Level Event(2014)

Finalist in Gujarat State, Honoured to receive a trophy by GM of Uninor

LANGUAGES

English, Hindi, Gujarati

MagicBox — Engineer

AUGUST 2011 - MAY 2013

- Develop product by efficient code and review and debug the code Perform validation and verification testing
- Document development phases and monitor systems
- Learn new technology to upgrade software and utilities
- Prioritize and execute tasks in the software development life cycle

EDUCATION

Gujarat University, Ahmedabad — Bachelor Of Computer Science

JUNE 2007 - MAY 2011